

DATA SCIENTIST · ECONOMICS RESEARCHER

Av. de Valdemarin 91A 1°D, 28023, Madrid, Spain

□ (+34) 651 808 171 | work [at] pabloforero.eu | Apabloforero.eu | pforero | pablo-forero

Summary

Data Scientist at Allfunds' Innovation Lab. Strong analytical and technological skills. Specialist in modelling and predictive analysis. Stochastic models, time series, dynamic programming, machine learning, and neural networks. Enthusiast about open source software and modern industry practices.

Work Experience _____

Allfunds Madrid, Spain

DATA SCIENTIST, INNOVATION LAB

2018 - Present

- Developed a predictive model using Random Forests, in order to profile retail costumers fund buying preferences.
- · Started an experimental project for classifying share classes using Natural Language Processing with prospectus in PDF format.
- Defined and analysed a project to implement a company wide CRM.
- Assisted in the development of a company Datalake built using Google Cloud.
- Created a Python tool for a systematic analysis of prices.
- Developed a pipeline of internal information and advanced analytics for management reporting.
- Assisted in the development of a new cloud based rebate calculation tool.
- · Created a module used to generate in the cloud the reporting of prices for internal and external users.

SAIS John Hopkins University

Bologna, Italy

TEACHING ASSISTANT

2015

• Teaching assistant in International Trade for Professor G. Plummer.

Banif (Santander Private Banking)

Madrid, Spain

ANALYST, ASSET MANAGEMENT

2009 - 2010

- · Analysis of assets and portfolios for asset managers.
- Generate the weekly reporting of the fixed income portfolios.

Renaissance Capital

London, UK

INTERN, RESEARCH

2008

· Research on Sub-saharan emerging markets.

cqs

London, UK

INTERN, RESEARCH

2008

2007

· Assisted portfolio managers on the analysis of firms, specially their pension liabilities.

ING Capital
Intern, Research

London, UK

• Research on Easter European emerging markets and Iberian utilities.

Education

European University Institute

Florence, Italy

Ph.D. (ABD) IN ECONOMICS

2012 - 2017

- Thesis title: Competition, Tasks and Earnings Inequality
- Supervisor: Ramon Marimón
- Research in International Trade, Macroeconomics, Labour Economics and Computational Economics

European University Institute

Florence, Italy

MRES IN ECONOMICS

2012 - 2013

Universidad de Navarra

MSc in Economics and Finance

Pamplona, Spain 2010 - 2011

University of Exeter

Exeter, UK

B.A. IN ECONOMICS AND POLITICS

2006 - 2009

Professional Activities

EABCN Training School Florence, Italy

2016

2016

PARTICIPANT

• Micro-Structure of Trade - Theory and Evidence

• Taught by Klaus Adam

Workshop on Economic Policy Challenges Florence, Italy

DISCUSSANT

• The Optimal Inflation Rate and Firm-Level Productivity Trends

• By Klaus Adam and Henning Weber

The Econometric Society 2016 European Winter Meeting Edinburgh, UK

Presenting 2016

Simposio de la Asociación Española de Economía

Bilbao, Spain

Presenting 2016

Zurich Initiative on Computational EconomicsZurich, Switzerland

Participant 2015

COEURE Workshop on Labour Markets

Brussels, Belgium

RAPPORTFUR 2015

• EU Dual Labour Markets: Consequences and Potential Reforms

Skills_

Research International Trade, Macroeconomics, Labour Economics, Computational Economics

Languages Spanish, English, French (Basic), Italian (Basic)

Programming Languages Python, Matlab, SQL, LaTeX, Julia, VBA

Statistical ToolsExcel, Dynare, Eviews, StataCloud ToolsGoogle Cloud Platform, BigQuery

Technology Tools Docker, Git, Office, Sphinx, Airflow, PyTorch